Guide to the China Records Project Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Papers of Individuals: N - Z, Series III
  - Rawlinson, Frank J.
    - Correspondence: Letters to his wife, 1917-1936 (Box 161, Folder 34-37)
    - Correspondence: Letter from Guy C. Stockton, 1923 (Box 161, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence: Letter from Brewer Eddy, 1935 (Box 161, Folder 39)
    - Print material primarily re. death of Frank Rawlinson reprint from "The Chinese Recorder" by FJR; pamphlet ed. by FJR, 1931-1940 (Box 161, Folder 40)
    - Typescript poem by Frank Rawlinson, 1948 (Box 161, Folder 41)
    - Printed material: "Musings of a Wayfarer" by Frank Rawlinson, 1930 (Box 161, Folder 42)
    - Photograph: 178 N. Szechuen Road, Shanghai Rawlinson home (Box 161, Folder 43)
  - Rawlinson, John
    Biog. info: son of Frank J. Rawlinson; Professor of History at Hofstra University
    - Typescript manuscript of John Rawlinson's book that was published as Rawlinson, The Recorder, and China's Revolution (1991). The 1040 page typescript is different in format from the published version, being in strictly chronological order. (1 of 2 boxes) (Box 363)
    - Typescript manuscript of John Rawlinson's book (2 of 2 boxes) (Box 364)
  - Rawlinson, Ruth
    Biog. info: daughter of Frank J. Rawlinson
    - Correspondence to family, 1936 (Box 162, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: 1 roll microfilm, 1902-1924 (Box 162, Folder 2)
  - Reed, Alice C.*
    Biog. info: ABCFM Tehchow (L.1921-L.1940)
    - Typescript ms. Excerpts from letters, 1916-1948 (Box 163, Folder 1-2)
    - Photos (Box OV4)
  - Reed, Bertha P.
    Reed served under the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions in Peking.
    - Three personal letters and three circular letters from Reed in Peking describe in detail Chinese civil war and political disruption, 1925-1926 (Box 376, Folder 6)
  - Rees, William Hopkyn
    Rees (1859-1924)was a Welsh missionary who joined the LMS North China mission in 1888 and later served as general secretary of the Christian Literature Society for China Society.
    - Seven photographs related to Rees, including portraits, and his grave, No date (Box 385, Folder 10)
  - Reik, Elsie
    Biog. info: MEFB, WFMS Foochow; Hwa Nan College, Foochow; Yenping
    - Photograph (Box 163, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1928 (Box 163, Folder 4-5)
    - Letters from Elsie Reik, 1924-1938 (Box 163, Folder 6-15)
    - Letter from Edna Reik, 1939, 1940 (Box 163, Folder 16)
    - Letter from Edith Abel, 1944 (Box 163, Folder 17)
    - Typescript essay: "Four Famous Chinese Beauties" (Box 163, Folder 18)
    - Collected material: "Hwa Nan's Celebration of Lydia A. Trimble's Jubilee by various authors, Foochow; "Program of the fifth Annual Commencement of the Hwa Nan College and Hwa Nan Middle School, 1925, 1949 (Box 163, Folder 19)
    - Typescript stories: "Kuan T'ai" by Myrth Bartlett, Parents' Magazine, "The story of the bamboo" by B.E. Newcome, "Hegira", 1933, 1938 (Box 163, Folder 20)
    - Typescript material: Program, Farewell Chapel, Foochow, Map information on Foochow Conference Methodist Episcopal Mission and WFMS, 1933 (Box 163, Folder 21)
  - Reinhard, August H.*
    Biog. info: Houlding South Chihli Mission (1904-1918) Milton Stewart Evangelistic Funds (1920-1921, 1925-1934) Independent Shanghai, Shan. (1936-1940) Shanghai Hebrew Mission (1940-1943)
    - Typescript autobiography (Box 236, Folder 7)
  - Reuman, Otto G. and Martha
    Biog. info: ABCFM Foochow (L.1919-1926)
    - List of material given (Box 164, Folder 1)
    - Typescript articles and letters, 1919-1925 (Box 164, Folder 2)
    - Printed material re. Foochow, Fukien (Box 164, Folder 3)
    - Printed material re. Religious Education (Box 164, Folder 4)
    - Collected materials: "A Study of Boys' Work (Box 164, Folder 5)
    - Printed material: Projects in international friendship, 1969 (Box 164, Folder 6)
    - Printed material: Foochow Trenches - leaflet for friends in USA or Foochow Goodwill Trenches, 1923-1925 (Box 164, Folder 7)
    - Pamphlets on boys work and Religious Education, 1923 (Box 164, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper clipping re. obituary of Reuman, New Haven Journal-Courier, 1972 (Box 164, Folder 9)
    - Photographs: Albums re. village life, street life, farming, river life, Chinese art, industry life, shrines, building, flood, fire, China Pictures, work and religiousneducation, boy scouts, boys club work, American boys club, student volunteers for ministry, etc. Foochow, China, 1919-1925 (Box 165, Folder 1-2)
    - Photograph and negatives (Box 165, Folder 3)
    - Pamphlets: "Program and Method of Organization for Older Boys", "Stories of Great Americans", "The Boy Scouts Association of China", "Christianity and Civilization", "Volunteer Bulletin", "Manual for Boys Club Leaders", 1919, 1922, 1924 (Box 165, Folder 4)
    - Photograph album documenting American Board Mission at Foochow, 1919-1925 (Box OV5)
      Including Sunday School work, Daily Vacation Bible School work, athletic meets, Foochow College, YMCA, Wenshan Girls School
  - Rhodes, Janet Smith
    Biog. info: Daughter of Yenching University faculty
    - Typescript material: Yenching Faculty Families Newsletters, 1986-1998 (Box 313, Folder 7)
  - Richardson, Agnes (Mrs. Robert Price)
    Biog. info: PS Taichow, Kiangsu (1923-1950)
    - Typescript material: Biographical data of Agnes Rowland Richardson 1898- Three short sketches (Box 166, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence from H. Kerr Taylor to Agnes concerning her book, 1970 (Box 166, Folder 5)
    - Book review of Agnes Richardson's "The Claimed Blessing" from The Cincinnati Inquirer, Cincinnati, 1970 (Box 166, Folder 6)
  - Richardson, Robert Price
    - Typescript material: Biographical Data - sketch by his son Edgar M. Richardson; Anonymous sketch, 1970 (Box 166, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence to his children, 1949-1950 (Box 166, Folder 8-9)
    - Correspondence from A. Baron Holmes, III to R.P. Richardson concerning his personal diary, 1944 (Box 166, Folder 10)
    - Typescript ms: Personal Diary, 1941-1942 (Box 166, Folder 11-17)
  - Rietveld, Harriet A.
    Biog. info: YWCA Shanghai, Chefoo, Sung. (L.1921-L.1927)
    - Correspondence: Letter from T.Z. Koo to friend, Peiping, 1933 (Box 167, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Letter to Mrs. Teague from Harriet A. Reitveld, New York, 1941 (Box 167, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Letter to friends at home from Lois Anna Ely, Shanghai, 1941 (Box 167, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Newsletter to China Mission friends from friends in the China Mission, Shanghai, 1941 (Box 167, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript poem: "Attitudinal Resolution" by Oliver Clemens James, 1931 (Box 167, Folder 5)
    - Printed article: "A Pilgrimage to Wu Tai Shan" by Irene M. Dean, The Chinese Publications, Wu Tai Shan, 1934 (Box 167, Folder 6)
    - Printed report of Child Labor Commission, Shanghai Municipal Council, Shanghai, 1924 (Box 167, Folder 7)
    - Collected material: "Social Creeds of the Christian Church, China, Conference Program, Institute of International Relations, Berkeley, California, 1930 (Box 167, Folder 8)
  - Riggs, Edward and Frances
    Biog. info: ABCFM, Edward was a medical doctor in Shaowu, Fukien; Frances was the daughter of Robert and Louise Gulick Whitaker, also ABCFM missionaries
    - "Mother and Daddy's Story" by Frances Riggs, 1994 (Box 360, Folder 1)
    - 10 circular letters of Ed Riggs, 1947, 1949 (Box 378, Folder 5)
  - Riggs, Grace F.
    ABCFM, Nanking
    - Circular letter, 1947 (Box 378, Folder 6)
  - Rinden, Arthur O. and Gertrude
    Biog. info: ABCFM Fukien 1926-1940
    - Excerpt from memoir; circular letter (Box 360, Folder 2)
  - Ritter, Richard H.
    Biog. info: PN Peking Yenching Univ. (c.1923-1924)
    - Typescript ms. "Memories of Princeton Court in Peking" by Richard H. Ritter '17 (Box 167, Folder 9)
  - Roberts, Issachar J.
    Independent American missionary of Baptist background
    - One issue of "The Oriental and Chinese Advocate", a monthly devoted to advocacy of China missions published and edited by I. J. Roberts, 1856 (Box 378, Folder 19)
  - Roberts Family: Roberts, William P. (Bishop) Roberts, Mrs. William P. Roberts, Donald Roberts, Frances
    Biog. info: ACM Shanghai (1914-1950) ACM Shanghai St. John's Univ. (1915-L.1940)
    - Photographs (Box 168, Folder 1-5)
    - Correspondence of Bishop William Roberts, incl. letter to his mother regarding the Nanking Incident, letter from government official, letter regarding return to the U.S. in 1950, 1927-1950 (Box 169, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence of Donald and Frances Roberts to family at home, 1927-1949 (Box 169, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence of Donald Roberts to Frances and children, 1941 Dec - 1942 Jan (Box 169, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence of Donald and Frances Roberts to their children, 1949 Jan - 1950 Aug (Box 169, Folder 4-6)
    - Correspondence of Donald and Frances Roberts to others, incl. William Myers, Marietta Atwood, Lloyd Craighill, Nelson Liu, 1927-1952 (Box 169, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence of others, incl. Bishop Graves, Roland Koh, 1925-1927 (Box 169, Folder 8)
    - Writings and notes: Frances Roberts: article in The Shanghai Newletter, 1949 Mar (Box 169, Folder 9)
    - Writings and notes: Donald Roberts: including "Famine Relief Work in the Ho-Su-Hsien Area" (1921); "Record of Our Life in the Pootung Civilian Assembly Center" (1943); "The Periodical Tien Hsia Monthly as a Source for Studies in Chinese Cultural History"; "The Imperial Sun Yat-Sen Theories of Government" (1931), 1921-1948 (Box 169, Folder 10-12)
    - Writings and notes: Donald Roberts: Notes for lectures re. internment camp, Tien Hsia Monthly (Box 169, Folder 13)
    - Writings and notes: Ellis N. Tucker: "Farewell to Teaching" (Box 169, Folder 14)
    - Biographical information (Box 169, Folder 15)
    - Collected material: articles re. China, prayer for China brochure, District of Shanghai Newsletters (1928-1930); Report of a Consultation on China Missionary Policy (1953) (Box 169, Folder 16)
    - Typescript Shanghai Newsletters with reports from missionaries (1950); Shanghai Newsletters and Supplement (1952, 1954, 1956, 1960, 1961) (Box 169, Folder 17-19)
    - Assembly Times (1943 - Pootung); miscellaneous China related clippings, 1922-1969 (Box 169, Folder 20-21)
    - Chinese dictionaries and study guide, 1917 (Box 169, Folder 22)
    - Photographs: Albums "Pancoast 1914 and Far East Trip" (a gift to the Roberts from the Pancoasts), "Chinese friends, etc. 1916 and 1937, 1949" (Box 170, Folder 1-2)
    - Photographs: Album "Pancoast Far East Trips 1914, 1923" (Box OV5)
  - Robinson, (Robbins, Rabinowitz), Jay
    - Correspondence: Letter from Jay Robinson to Sirs, letter to Jay Robinson from John C. Corbin, incl. photo of the 1921-22 class at North China Language School, Peking, 1921-1922, 1965-1966 (Box 172, Folder 1)
  - Robinson Family
    Hugh Laughton Robinson, M.D., and his wife Olga Olsen Robinson served under the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions in Lintsing, Tunghsien (1926-1941). Robinson was chief of the Tungchou Hospital 1932-1941.
    - Memoirs, autobiography of Olga Olsen (Mrs. Hugh Laughlin), "The Robinson Saga", 73 p. mimeo*; circular letter; letters of Hugh Robinson, M.D.; "The Lintsing Memorial Hospital during War and Famine"; illustration of layout of American Board Mission in Paotingfu, 1927-1974 (Box 172, Folder 2)
    - Video interviews with four children of Hugh L. and Olga Olsen Robinson, conducted by Mayumi Robinson, great-granddaughter of the Robinsons (4 DVDs), 2012 (Box 375, Folder 1)
  - Rohlfs, Mae
    Biog. info: ALM Tsingtao
    - Corres., newsletters, bulletins, 1949-1952 (Box 172, Folder 3)
  - Roots, Logan and Frances
    Biog. info.: ACM Logan Roots was the son of Logan H. Roots (1870-1945) who was Bishop in Hankow. Frances Roots Hadden was his sister, the daughter of Bishop Roots.
    - Loose photographs: family and scenes in Peking, 1932-1934 (Box 338, Folder 47)
    - Loose photographs: Peking Language School, Peking Union Medical School, 1932-1934 (Box 338, Folder 48)
    - Loose photographs and postcards: scenes in Peking, 1932-1934 (Box 338, Folder 49)
    - Photo album of Frances Roots: scenes in Peking, 1934-1935 (Box 338, Folder 50)
    - Photo album of Frances Roots: scenes in Kuling, Kiangsi; scenes of 1930 flood Hankow; Iron pagoda; Temple of Hell, 1930-1935 (Box 338, Folder 51)
  - Rothe, Jean B.
    - Letters received by the donor (Mrs. Rothe), "The China Colleges" Dec. 1946 issue, 1932-1935, 1946, 1949 (Box 172, Folder 4)
  - Rowland, Henry Hosie and Rowland, Mildred May Ament (Mrs. Henry H.)
    Biog. info: MEFB Changli, Lanhsien, Tientsin (1911-1922)
    - Correspondence, 1912-1941 (Box 172, Folder 5-9)
    - Typescript writings: "The Changli Middle and Higher Primary School", "The Story of a Chinese Girl (Miss Mu)", etc., 1911, 1919, 1920 (Box 172, Folder 10)
  - Rowland, Marion Jean
    - Correspondence: Letters from Marion Jean Rowland primarily to family, 1948-1950 (Box 172, Folder 11-16)
    - Correspondence: Letter from Jennie B. Bridenbaugh to friends, to E.J. Winnans fromWilliam Hsu, 1923, 1948 (Box 172, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: Letter to Henry H. Rowland from Myrtle A. Snuth, to friends from Louise Robinsin, 1949, 1950 (Box 172, Folder 18)
    - Typescript ms. "Our Story" by Jean Rowland (Lowe), (Alice Weed, and others), Kienyang, Szechuan, 1949-1950 (Box 172, Folder 19)
  - Rue, Margaret Mary and Elizabeth Rue Hembold
    Biog. info: MES Changchow, Ku. Wusih, Ku. (L.1924-L.1940)
    - Correspondence, 1935-1958 (Box 173, Folder 1-5)
    - Printed material, photograph, misc. (Box 173, Folder 6)
    - Typescript writings, essays, play scripts, etc.: "Flight", "Evangelistic work in Wusih, Ku., China", "Impressions of camp no. 100", "One month among the bandits", "Palm Sunday play", etc. (Box 173, Folder 7)
    - News material: "Trans-Pacific News Service", 1938 (Box 173, Folder 8)
    - Pamphlets: "Legislation to Prohibit War Exports to Japan" by Henry Stimson, "They too Came Back", re. Korea Missionaries, "The Great White War" by H.V. Kaltenborn, "In Loving Memory of Nora Lambuth Park 1863-1949", "Kung SAm Lee A Chinese Christian Businessman and former successful exchange Broker who has a stirring message for America!" (Box 173, Folder 9)
    - Misc. material incl. "Win Christ for China through Radio!", Report from :The American Committee for Non-Participation in Japanese Aggression", "a Creed for Americans", etc. (Box 173, Folder 10)
  - Ruland, Lloyd S.
    Presbyterian mission board administrator
    - 2 circular letters from trip to China, 1939 (Box 378, Folder 7)
  - Russell, W.B.
    Biog. info: Russell (1882-1925) was a medical missionary in Soochow, China where he died of typhoid fever. He served as superintendent of the Changchow General Hospital from 1918 until his death.
    - Photographs mostly re. Stevenson Memorial Hospital, 1918, 1924-1925, 1932, 1984 (Box 315, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, etc., 1987-1988 (Box 315, Folder 17)
  - St. Clair, Bertha Harding Allen (Mrs. Arthur E.)
    Biog. info: ABCFM Foochow (1916-1941)
    - Photographs: People, schools, scenes, 1917-1946 (Box 174, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1916-1941 (Box 174, Folder 2-6)
    - Letter from G.W. Hinnan, 1936, 1939 (Box 174, Folder 7)
    - Typescript report re. Foochow Union Kindergarten Training School, 1919-1950 (Box 174, Folder 8)
  - Salmon, Frances King, M.D. and Robert J.
    Biog. info: Shanghai Women's Medical Coll. St. John's Univ. (1922-1940)
    - Photographs re. people, hospital, occupations, buildings and other scenes, 1814, 1907, 1922-1934 (Box 175, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence, 1923-1927 (Box 175, Folder 3)
    - Printed material incl. "Unusual Experiences in Practice of Obstetrics and Gynecology in China" by G.C. Schauffler, 1924-1948 (Box 175, Folder 4)
    - Printed correspondence (from newspaper) from Frances King, 1923-1927 (Box 175, Folder 5)
    - Chinese Language Newspapers (Box 175, Folder 6)
    - Pamphlets: "General Statistics of the Chung Hua Sheng Kung Hui" by M.H.Throop, 1936 (Box 175, Folder 7)
    - Photographs: Albums re. trip to Japan and China, people, occupation and others, 1926-1930 (Box 176, Folder 1-2)
  - Sargent, Douglas and Imogene
    CMS, Kweilin, Hunan, Hong Kong
    - 6 circular letters, 1949 (Box 378, Folder 8)
  - Satterthwaite, Adaline and David
    - Circular letter from T'ungchow, 1951 (Box 378, Folder 9)
  - Schaefer, Alice H.
    Schaeffer was an American Presbyterian missionary who served in Canton beginning in 1938 and later in Hong Kong.
    - Circular letter from Hong Kong, 1961 (Box 375, Folder 2)
  - Schleman, Laura
    Biog. info: WFMS/MEFB Kiukiang, Kiangsi
    - Scrapbook (Box 262, Folder 5)
  - Schubert, William E.
    Biog. info: MEFB Shanghai, Nanchang, Kiangsu, Kiukiang, Ki. (L.1923-L.1940)
    - Tapes: 13 tapes in 12 boxes--a memo from Donald E. MacInnis states: "These tapes are copies from originals made by Rev. Wm. Schubert, interviewed by his daughter, Esther. Mr. Schubert spent many years as a Methodist missionary in China, and since 1950, in the Philippines and Japan." (n.d.) (Box 185, Folder 1)
    - Audio tapes: Schubert (18 nos.) (Box 185a)
    - Writing by Schubert re. John Sung; coverletter to Donald MacInnis, 1972 (Box 357, Folder 3)
    - Issues of Revival News, 1955-1972 (Box 357, Folder 4)
  - Scott, Katherine
    - Printed essay (Biographical): "Katherine Scott" by Grace Hutchins, 1924 (Box 186, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence from Katherine Scott, 1910-1911 (Box 186, Folder 2)
  - Scott, Roderick
    Biog. info: ABCFM Foochow Fukien Xn. Univ. (1916-1949) see also: China Missionary Oral History Collection
    - Typescript ms: "The Personalistic Insights in Ancient Chinese Philosophy" (295 pp. Ph.D. dissertation for the U. of Southern Calif.); circular letter, 1946, 1947 (Box 186, Folder 3-16)
  - Seaton, Stuart P. (M.D.)
    Biog. info: PN Hoihow, Hainan, Kwangtung Nodoa, Tung. Kachek, Tung. (L.1926-L.1940)
    - Printed material: "How Can We Build A New China and a New World?" by Sherwood Eddy, in an address to the CSCA Eastern Summer Conference, 1942 (Box 187, Folder 1)
    - Printed material: "South China Morning Post", 1927 (Box 187, Folder 2)
    - Pamphlet: "Christian World Facts for the use of ministers", 1941 (Box 187, Folder 3)
    - Clippings (Box 187, Folder 4)
    - Map of Hankow incl. Chinese art (Box 187, Folder 5)
    - Collected mateiral: Handwoven slippers (Chinese) (Box 187, Folder 6)
  - Selden, Charles C. (M.D.) and Gertrude
    Biog. info: PN; John G. Kerr Hospital for the Insane, Canton (1897-1938)
    - Manuscript poem by CCS: "One Chinese Maiden" (Box 188, Folder 1)
    - Printed material: Booklet by CCS: "Pearls from the Pearl River", 1939 (Box 188, Folder 2)
    - Personal and biog. material, newsclipping, memorial tributes, booklet by Mrs. Seldon, family letter, musical compositions, Gertrude's will, 1895-1944 (Box 188, Folder 3)
  - Sellemeyer, Esther I.
    Biog. info: RCUS Shenchowfu, Hun. (L.1917-L.1930)
    - Correspondence (alphabetical sequence) (Box 189, Folder 1-15)
    - Correspondence (alphabetical sequence) (Box 190, Folder 1-9)
    - Chinese Language material, 1920? (Box 190, Folder 10)
    - Diary, 1918 (Box 190, Folder 11)
    - Photographs: Shenchow Girls' School Cornerstone Laying Ceremonies, execution of criminals, photos of Esther since in China, etc., 1900, 1917-1928 (Box 191, Folder 1)
    - Printed material incl. "The Nanking Handbook", "Imperial Palace Museum Peking", "An Oriental Necklace of Needs", "Information for Travellers landing at Shanghai", etc., 1916, 1923 (Box 191, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings primarily concerning Esther Sellemeyer, 1917, 1918 (Box 191, Folder 3)
    - Chinese Language material (Box 191, Folder 4)
    - Map of Hunan Postal District, 1928 (Box OV1)
    - Scrolls honoring Sellemeyer, No date (Box OV1)
  - Selsbee, Elizabeth
    - Printed material: "China's Industrial Cooperatives" Reprint from Craft Horizons, 1947 (Box 188, Folder 4)
  - Sewell, Ruth M.
    Ruth Sewall was the daughter of China missionaries William and Hilda Sewell. She attended Mount Holyoke College (class of 1923, non-graduate). She taught at the Methodist Girls' High School in Nanking duing 1926-1927. Political disruption in China forced evacuation of missionaries in her area and she returned to the U.S. where she married Russell Scudder.
    - Letters written from Nanking and enroute to the U.S.; two photographs and newspaper clippings, 1926-1927 (Box 334, Folder 1)
    - Photocopies of the letters and news clippings, 1926-1927 (Box 334, Folder 2)
    - Two dolls, one from China and one from Japan (Box 334, Folder 3)
  - Shaw, Ella C.*
    Biog. info: EFMS Nanking (1887-1934)
    - Typescript memoir/history: "History of Ella C. Shaw's Work in Nanking", transcribed by Celia B. Steward, c.1930 (Box 188, Folder 5)
  - Shaw, Ernest T.*
    Biog. info: ABCFM Tunghsien, Peking (1912-1951)
    - Biographical statement re. Ernest Shaw; compilation of typescript letters from North China 1912-1915 (Box 188, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 188, Folder 7)
  - Shaw, Sarah Lizzie Burnham
    Shaw, wife of William Shaw, served under the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions in Paotingfu from 1880 until her death in 1882.
    - 10 handwritten letters from Shaw primarily to her Grandmother Burnham from Paotingfu; 1 letter from William Shaw announces the birth of their son Ellliott Locke Shaw, who died shortly after his mother in 1882., 1880-1882 (Box 375, Folder 3)
  - Sheets, Margaret
    Biog. info: ACM Huachung University (1946-1950) Sheets taught English at Huachung, but much of the material in this collection was collected or received by Sheets following her return from China.
    - Correspondence: Friends and students - A-C (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Friends and students - Chen, Muzhu and Julia (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Friends and students - Chen, Shih Lu (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Friends and students - F-Y (Box 9, Folder 4-6)
    - Correspondence: Friends and students - Xu Zu-Yi (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Friends and students - Zhu, Suzanne and Andrew Yang (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Writings, Term Papers, including - "A New Imperative";"Old men in Wordsworth's Poetry"; "Cazamian's Approach to Literary History"; "The Cenci"; "Shakespeare's Reliance on Plutarch in the characterization of Anthony and Cleopatra" (Box 9, Folder 9-24)
    - Writings, Short Story Book Reports (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Writings, Exam Books (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Writings, Misc. Pages (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Writings, Others; Anderson - Major Trends in Teaching English (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Biographical Information and Memorabilia: Personal Notes - Missionary Experiences (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Biographical Information and Memorabilia: Language Study (Box 9, Folder 30-32)
    - Biographical Information and Memorabilia: Greeting cards and Postcards (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Biographical Information and Memorabilia: Programs and Misc. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Biographical Information and Memorabilia: Chinese Banners, Personal tributes (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Biographical Information and Memorabilia: Obituaries - others (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Photographs: M. Sheets alone and with others (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Photographs: People (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
    - Photographs: Transportation and work (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Photographs: Buildings and scenery (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Photographs: Album, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Photographs: Comparing Scenes 1947 and 1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Subject and Collected Items: International Missionary Council Conference, Jul 1952 (Box 10, Folder 12)